

Date of Birth 12/07/1989

Mobility

Full Driving License

Telephone

+447855436230

Email

Andrew.lreland@me.com

Address

Flat 6, Marlborough Hall 30 Mapperley Road Nottingham NG3 5AN

Website

Andrewireland.co.uk

Social

@Andyi1989 /In/Andrewireland89

Hobbies

Music (Drummer) Cycling & Mountain Biking Technology & Computing

Skills

Product Management
Product Team Management
Product Development
Product Strategy & Business Plans
Advanced Plumbing
Advanced Gas
Computing

Reference

Mr Mark Barson

Future Technologies Manager

Vaillant Group Ltd Nottingham Road

Belper DE56 1JT

Tel: 07870 989131

Email: Mark.Barson@Vaillant-

Group.co.uk

ANDREW IRELAND - CURRICULUM VITAE

Personal Profile

Hello, I'm an experienced Product Manager & fully qualified Gas Engineer with over 15 years history of working in the heating, renewables and environment industry.

In my career, I have been launching and managing hardware and software products in a portfolio of industry-leading products, providing onsite & offsite support, running training courses, speaking at events, supporting internal staff and working with trade associations to support legislation and industry.

Experience

Digital Technologies Development Manager - Feb 2017 - Present

In this role I manage a team of product managers and engineers who are responsible for the IoT, API & digital propositions as well as a large range of connected and non connected heating controls & thermostats for a broad range of technologies. Alongside this, I'm responsible for managing the digital product strategy and roadmap and ensuring the successful delivery of products into the UK market, working closely with trade associations and working groups on future industry regulation.

Product Manager - Controls & Systems - May 2015 - Feb 2017

In this role i'm responsible for launching new products into the UK market as well as developing and maintaining the portfolio of existing industry leading products. Monitoring product sales volumes, margins, reliability and managing the resolution of all product specification and reliability issues working closely with all internal stakeholders, group programme management, quality and R&D. Co-ordinating with brand marketing and internal departments to innovate, develop strategies and product argumentation for new and existing products, whilst supporting the sale teams with detailed technical solutions, product information and training as required.

System Technologies Engineer, Vaillant Group UK Ltd — 2013 - May 2015

In this role I provided technical, design and practical assistance for Controls, Ground Source & air source heat pumps, Mechanical Ventilation, Air conditioning and Hybrid Systems for consultants, specifiers and installers for multiple bands. Developed applications supporting the sales force, product management & system technologies accessing and distributing information, carrying out calculations and generating specifications.

Technical Officer, Vaillant Ltd - 2011-2013

In this role I provided over the phone technical support covering current industry standards, gas boilers, system controls and renewable technologies, created a suite of schematics to support internal and external customers, created a intranet and suite of tools to support the technical team in providing information efficiently whilst ensuring a great service to the customer.

Apprenticeship, K. Palmer Plumbing & heating Services 2007-2011

During this role I worked in customers' homes and businesses, installing and repairing boilers, gas fires, kitchens, bathrooms, under floor heating, central heating, cookers and drainage systems. Annually serviced gas appliances and provided Landlord Safety Checks. Establishing good customer relations.

Professional Development & Education

City and Guilds

Gas Installations (CCN1, CEN1, CKR1, HTR1, CPA1)

NVQ level 3 in mechanical engineering services - plumbing & gas

BPEC

Unvented hot water storage systems Solar domestic hot water systems

Certificate in energy efficiency for domestic heating Water supply (Water Fittings) Regulations 1999

Domestic Heat Pumps

Other

Uponor course on underfloor heating systems CADline aCADemy training on autoCAD software Google Digital Garage - Digital Marketing course

Education

2000 - 2005 Lindsay School 2005 - 2010 Grimsby Institue